Simon Ugorji

Aba, Abia State, Nigeria



ugorji757@gmail.com



+2348162273445



linkedin.com/in/simon-ugorji-57a6a41a3

Summary

I'm Ugorji Simon Okorie, a Full-Stack Web Developer from Nigeria.

I have worked with PHP and JavaScript for 3 years now and I have a solid experience building web Apps and projects in both languages.

I am a self-taught developer and would be glad to accept an internship offer to sharpen my skills.

As part of my learning process, I write technical articles on medium, hashnode, tealfeed and dev community and I love to work on side projects.

I have experience in HTML, CSS, ReactJS, PHP, MySQL, NodeJs, MongoDB, and Express JS.

I currently have 7 active side projects.

I am a tech enthusiast and would love to see myself as a computer scientist one day.

Experience



Technical Writer

Hashnode

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month)

I write and publish technical articles on Hashnode

Visit my blog at: https://octagon.hashnode.dev

Technical Writer

Tealfeed

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month)

I write and publish technical articles on Tealfeed

Visit my blog at: https://tealfeed.com/simon_ugorji

Technical Writer

Medium

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month)

I write and publish technical articles on medium and my articles receive an average of 1.5K views every week

Visit my blog at: https://simon-ugorji.medium.com

Full-Stack Web Developer

Innovation Growth Hub

Aug 2022 - Present (5 months)

I got the opportunity to be part of a huge community on August 2022.

I'm learning new ways of thinking and also gaining experience in project presentations by participating in Hackathons and tech events.

Some of the skills I acquired are; ReactJS, NodeJS, and MongoDB

Back End Web Developer

Vistacool Technologies Limited

Sep 2021 - Oct 2022 (1 year 2 months)

I built an admin portal that is being used to monitor device installations and customers activities with their products.

I worked closely with other developers and I mostly used PHP and JavaScript in this role

Software Engineer Intern

alx_africa

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022 (7 months)

Education



Higher National Diploma, Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering Sep 2019 - Aug 2022

Licenses & Certifications

- Control panel university cPanel
- **U** JavaScript Programming Foundations Udacity
- Spark AR Creator Day Meta
- Building Web Applications in PHP Coursera
 VZFVX235P9J6
- Hack 2022 Participation Certificate Innovation Growth Hub

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate - Innovation Growth Hub

Skills

React.js • Node.js • JavaScript • PHP • Technical Writing • HTML5